Inventory of the Ruan Yicheng collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Ruan Yicheng collection
1953-1974
2007C49
Ruan, Yicheng, 1905-, collector.
35 manuscript boxes (14 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Printed matter, relating to the Zhongguo guo min dang, and to the government of Taiwan.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of materials collected by Ruan Yicheng, a member of the Kuomintang (KMT) Chinese Nationalist Party and of the Planning Committee of the Executive Yuan, 1951-1956. Documents include thirteen volumes of the KMT's Central Committee, 1954-1966; sixty-nine volumes of its Standing Committee, 1954-1966; twenty-three volumes of the Executive Yuan (executive branch of the central government), 1952-1971; thirty-one volumes of the Legislative Yuan (legislative branch of the central government), 1952-1970; seven volumes of the National Assembly, 1957-1963; and forty-nine volumes of miscellaneous documents.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Zhongguo guo min dang; China-Politics and government-1912-1949; Taiwan-Politics and government
Collection Contents
- National Party Congress Documents, 1957-1963; 1
  - Eighth Congress, 1957 (Folder 1)
    - 1st-14th meetings, 1957 October 14-23 (Folder 1)
  - Ninth Congress, 1963
    - 1st-14th meetings, 1963 November 13-22 (Folder 1)
- Central Committee Minutes of Meetings, Reports and Documents, 1953-1966 (Folder 2-4)
  - Seventh Session, 1953-1955 (Folder 2)
    - 2nd meeting, 1953 May (Folder 2)
    - 3rd meeting, 1953 November (Folder 2)
    - 4th meeting, 1954 August 2 (Folder 2)
    - 5th meeting, 1955 March 1 (Folder 2)
    - 6th meeting, 1955 October 3 (Folder 2)
  - Eighth Session, 1960-1962 (Folder 3)
    - 3rd meeting, 1960 September 29 (Folder 3)
    - 4th meeting, 1961 November 14 (Folder 3)
    - 5th meeting, 1962 November 15 (Folder 3)
  - Ninth Session, 1963-1966 (Folder 4)
    - 1st meeting, 1963 November 23 (Folder 4)
    - 2nd meeting, 1963 November 24 (Folder 4)
    - 3rd meeting, 1966 March 7 (Folder 4)
    - 4th meeting, 1966 December 26 (Folder 4)
- Central Standing Committee Minutes of Meetings, 1954-1966 (Folder 5-17)
  - Seventh Session, 1954-1956 (Folder 5-6)
    - 89th-127th meetings, 1954 March 15-July 21 (Folder 5)
    - 132nd-152nd meetings, 1954 August 11-November 3 (Folder 5)
    - 153rd-162nd meetings, 1954 November 10-December 22 (Folder 5)
    - 164th-174th meetings, 1955 January 5-February 23 (Folder 5)
    - 176th-198th meetings, 1955 March 9-June 1 (Folder 6)
    - 219th-231st meetings, 1955 September 14-November 16 (Folder 6)
    - 235th-248th meetings, 1955 November 30-1956 February 1 (Folder 6)
  - Eighth Session, 1961 February-December (Folder 7-11)
    - 278th-290th meetings, 1961-1963 (Folder 7)
    - 291st-295th meetings, 1961 April 15-29 (Folder 7)
    - 296th-300th meetings, 1961 May 3-24 (Folder 7)
    - 301st-305th meetings, 1961 May 27-June 14 (Folder 7)
    - 306th-310th meetings, 1961 June 17-July 8 (Folder 7)
    - 311th-312th meetings, 1961 July 12-15 (Folder 8)
    - 313th-315th meetings, 1961 July 22-29 (Folder 8)
    - 321st-325th meetings, 1961 September 2-20 (Folder 8)
    - 326th-331st meetings, 1961 October 4-28 (Folder 8)
    - 332nd-337th meetings, 1961 November 4-25 (Folder 8)
    - 338th-344th meetings, 1961 December 2-30 (Folder 8)
    - 345th-351st meetings, 1962 January 3-31 (Folder 9)
    - 352nd-356th meetings, 1961 February 3-24 (Folder 9)
    - 357th-364th meetings, 1962 February 28-March 31 (Folder 9)
    - 365th-370th meetings, 1962 April 4-28 (Folder 9)
    - 371st-377th meetings, 1962 May 2-30 (Folder 9)
    - 378th-381st meetings, 1962 June 2-30 (Folder 9)
    - 382nd-386th meetings, 1962 July 7-28 (Folder 10)
    - 387th-393rd meetings, 1962 August 1-29 (Folder 10)
    - 394th-399th meetings, 1962 September 1-29 (Folder 10)
    - 400th-405th meetings, 1962 October 3-27 (Folder 10)
    - 406th-411th meetings, 1962 November 3-28 (Folder 10)
    - 412th-420th meetings, 1962 December 1-29 (Folder 10)
    - 421st-424th meetings, 1963 January 5-30 (Folder 11)
    - 425th-431st meetings, 1963 February 2-27 (Folder 11)
    - 432nd-439th meetings, 1963 March 2-30 (Folder 11)
    - 440th-443rd meetings, 1963 April 10-27 (Folder 11)
    - 444th-449th meetings, 1963 May 1-29 (Folder 11)
    - 450th-454th meetings, 1963 June 1-29 (Folder 11)
    - 474th-481st meetings, 1963 October 2-23 (Folder 11)
  - Ninth Session, 1964-1966 (Folder 12-17)
    - 8th-14th meetings, 1964 January 8-29 (Folder 12)
    - 30th-37th meetings, 1964 April 1-25 (Folder 12)
    - 61st-67th meetings, 1964 August 1-29 (Folder 12)
    - 68th-76th meetings, 1964 September 2-30 (Folder 12)
    - 77th - 84th meetings, 1964 October 3-31 (Folder 12)
    - 85th-90th meetings, 1964 November 4-21 (Folder 12)
    - 91st-97th meetings, 1964 December 2-26 (Folder 13)
    - 98th-105th meetings, 1965 January 6-30 (Folder 13)
    - 105th-109th meetings, 1965 February 10-24 (Folder 13)
    - 110th-117th meetings, 1965 March 3-31 (Folder 13)
    - 118th-123rd meetings, 1965 April 3-28 (Folder 13)
    - 124th-130th meetings, 1965 May 5-26 (Folder 13)
    - 131st-138th meetings, 1965 June 2-30 (Folder 14)
    - 139th-145th meetings, 1965 July 7-28 (Folder 14)
    - 146th-151st meetings, 1965 August 9-25 (Folder 14)
    - 152nd-159th meetings, 1965 September 1-29 (Folder 14)
    - 160th-164th meetings, 1965 October 6-27 (Folder 14)
    - 165th-171st meetings, 1965 November 3-29 (Folder 14)
    - 172nd-177th meetings, 1965 December 1-27 (Folder 15)
    - 178th-184th meetings, 1966 January 5-31 (Folder 15)
    - 185th-191st meetings, 1966 February 2-28 (Folder 15)
    - 192nd-198th meetings, 1966 March 2-30 (Folder 15)
    - 199th-203rd meetings, 1966 April 4-27 (Folder 15)
    - 204th-212th meetings, 1966 May 2-27 (Folder 15)
    - 213th-221st meetings, 1966 May 30-June 29 (Folder 16)
    - 22nd-228th meetings, 1966 July 4-27 (Folder 16)
    - 229th-237th meetings, 1966 August 1-31 (Folder 16)
    - 238th-243rd meetings, 1966 September 7-26 (Folder 16)
    - 244th-248th meetings, 1966 October 3-24 (Folder 16)
    - 249th-256th meetings, 1966 November 2-30 (Folder 16)
    - 257th-262nd meetings, 1966 December 5-21 (Folder 17)
- Central Reform Committee Reports, undated (Folder 18)
  - 6th Plenary Session, undated (Folder 18)
  - 7th Plenary Session, undated (Folder 18)
- Central Work Review Committee Documents, 1961-1963 (Folder 18)
- Central Policy Committee Documents, 1961-1966 (Folder 19)
- Party Business Meetings Documents, 1961-1966 (Folder 20)
  - 6th Session, 1961 June (Folder 20)
  - 7th Session, 1962 June (Folder 20)
  - 8th Session, 1963 June (Folder 20)
  - 9th Session, 1964 July (Folder 20)
  - 10th Session, 1965 May (Folder 20)
  - 11th Session, 1966 June (Folder 20)
- Political Subcommittee on General Mobilization Movement to Resist Communism and Russia Minutes of Meetings, 1952-1971 (Folder 21-28)
  - 15th-17th Session, 1952 September 21-December 25 (Folder 21)
  - 18th-25th Session, 1953 January 8-July 17 (Folder 21)
  - 33rd-37th Session, 1954 November 23-1955 April 23 (Folder 21)
  - First Term, 195201971 (Folder 22-28)
    - Ninth Session, 1952 (Folder 22)
      - 1st-11th meetings, 1952 February 12-March 25 (Folder 22)
      - 12th-24th meetings, 1952 March 28-May 13 (Folder 22)
      - 25th-30th meetings, 1952 May 16-May 31 (Folder 22)
      - 2nd-13th confidential meetings, 1952 February 15-May 31 (Folder 22)
    - Eleventh Session, 1953 (Folder 23)
      - 1st-17th meetings, 1953 February 17-May 5 (Folder 23)
      - 1st-15th confidential meetings, 1953 February 24-June 27 (Folder 23)
    - Fifteenth Session, 1955 (Folder 23)
      - 2nd-23rd meetings, 1955 February 18-May 31 (Folder 23)
      - 1st-14th confidential meetings, 1955 March 1-May 31 (Folder 23)
    - Thirty-first Session, 1963 (Folder 24)
      - 1st-8th meetings, 1963 February 19-March 15 (Folder 24)
    - Thirty-third Session, 1964 (Folder 24)
      - 1st-17th meetings, 1964 February 21-May 1 (Folder 24)
      - 18th-34th meetings, 1964 May 5-July 14 (Folder 24)
      - 35th-42nd meetings, 1964 July 17-August 25 (Folder 24)
      - 1st-13th confidential meetings, 1964 March 3-August 25 (Folder 24)
    - Thirty-fifth Session, 1965 (Folder 25)
      - 19th confidential meeting, 1965 August 27 (Folder 25)
    - Thirty-sixth Session, 1965-1966 (Folder 25)
      - 1st-13th meetings, 1965 September 21-November 9 (Folder 25)
      - 1st-14th confidential meetings, 1965 November 16-1966 January 28 (Folder 25)
    - Thirty-seventh Session, 1966 (Folder 26)
      - 12th-28th meetings, 1966 April 19-June 28 (Folder 26)
      - 29th-42nd meetings, 1966 July 1-August 26 (Folder 26)
      - 1st-17th confidential meetings, 1966 April 18- August 23 (Folder 26)
    - Forty-sixth Session, 1970-1971 (Folder 27)
      - 1st-8th meetings, 1970 September 25-October 20 (Folder 27)
      - 9th-20th meetings, 1970 October 23-December 1 (Folder 27)
      - 21st-32nd meetings, 1970 December 4-1971 January 22 (Folder 27)
    - Forty-eighth Session, 1971 (Folder 28)
      - 1st-12th meetings, 1971 September 24-November 5 (Folder 28)
      - 13th-21st meetings, 1971 November 9-December 10 (Folder 28)
      - 1st confidential meetings, 1971 November 16 (Folder 28)
- Executive Yuan Records, 1951-1974 (Folder 29-31)
  - Nation building group, 1956-1957 (Folder 29)
  - Rights and responsibilities of various branches of the Executive Yuan, 1962 (Folder 29)
  - Economic planning committee, 1974 (Folder 29)
  - Executive Yuan committee proposals, 1951-1954 (Folder 30)
  - Executive Yuan administrative reports, 1956; 1951-1961 (Folder 31)
- Presidential Office Records, 1958 (Folder 32)
  - Administrative reform committee, 1958 (Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous Documents, 1950-1969 (Folder 33-37)
  - Financial expense reports, 1956 (Folder 33)
  - Fourth National Education Conference reports, 1962 (Folder 33)
  - First National Congress roster, 1954 (Folder 33)
  - Legal studies colloquium, 1955-1956 (Folder 33)
  - Party criticism and recommendations, 1954 (Folder 33)
  - Workshop on Revolution research, 1954-1961 (Folder 33)
  - Reconquering China Planning and Research Commission, 1962 (Folder 33)
  - Reconquering China planning and research committee, 1950-1962; 1964-1966 (Folder 34)
  - National defense research committee, 1958-1960 (Folder 34)
  - Sun Yat-sen Memorial Committee, 1964-1966 (Folder 34)
  - Administrative reform review report, 1963 (Folder 34)
  - Records of the Taipei mayoral elections, 1964 (Folder 34)
  - Presidential Office Report, 1967 (Folder 35)
  - Historical files, 1968 (Folder 35)
  - Taipei City development committee, 1958 (Folder 35)
  - Taiwan autonomous regions governing revision committee, 1960-1962 (Folder 35)
  - Various reports of Taiwan provinces, 1960 (Folder 35)
  - Five Proposals, 1966 (Folder 35)
  - State-run Operations annual expenditure reports, 1955-1969 (Folder 36)
    - 1955 (Folder 36)
    - 1956 (Folder 36)
    - 1961 (Folder 36)
    - 1969 (Folder 36)
  - Central Executive Committee documents, 1966-1969 (Folder 37)